Your Highness
전하
The edict is real
조서는 진짜입니다
It's real
진짜가 맞습니다
Your Highness
전하
The edict is real
조서는 진짜입니다
Where is Wen Xian?
온현은 어디 있느냐?
I sent him
짐이 시킨 대로
To deliver the message
전하라고 한 말은
Did he deliver it?
제대로 전했느냐?
Your Majesty
폐하
Eunuch Wen
온 공공은...
Was beheaded by Prince of Jin
진왕에게 참수당했습니다
Beheaded
참수
Good that he was beheaded
잘했어
Where is my canal?
짐의 운하는?
Is my canal finished?
짐의 운하는 다 완성됐느냐?
This
그게
What canal?
운하라니요
Where is my canal?
짐의 운하
Your Majesty
폐하
Your Majesty, slow down
폐하 천천히
The 24th year of Yuankang
원강 24년
Emperor Sikong Jing
황제 사공경은
Due to taking excessive elixirs
단약을 과다 복용한 데다
And rage affecting his heart
극심한 화병으로 인해
Suddenly passed away
급작스럽게 죽었습니다
At the same time
그리고 동시에
Your great army
당신의 대군은
Had already reached the capital
황성 턱밑까지 다다랐습니다
What did you tell me before?
그때는 나에게 뭐라 했습니까!
Saying Qingzhou Army would strike first
경주군이 선수를 쳤다느니
Dongming was impregnable
동명성이 철옹성이라느니
Now?
그런데 지금은?
How did it come to this?
지금 왜 이 지경이 되었냐 말이오!
Your Highness
전하
I'll go out personally
제가 직접 성 밖으로 나가
Command Qingzhou Army to advance
경주군을 지휘하겠습니다
As long as I'm there
제가 있는 한
Your Highness's trump card remains
전하의 패는 살아 있습니다
Trump card
패라고?
Right
그렇지
His greatest weakness
그놈의 가장 큰 약점이
Is still in my hands
아직 내 손안에 있지
I'll do as you say
승상의 말대로 합시다
I'll find a way to get you out
성 밖에 내보낼 테니
Remember
명심하세요
Must not make any mistakes
다시는 실수가 있어서는 안 됩니다
Brother
아우야
No matter what
누가 뭐래도
Family is still family
우린 한 핏줄인 가족 아니겠느냐
As your elder brother, I won't take advantage
형이 돼서 너의 약점을 이용할 생각은 없다
But sending out the Princess Consort
허나 왕비를 내보내려면
Requires opening the gates
성문을 열어야 하는데
This is too dangerous for me
이건 내게 너무나 위험한 일이다
Order your army to retreat thirty li
너의 군대를 30리 밖으로 물리면
I'll send someone to escort the Princess Consort out
내가 사람을 보내 왕비를 성 밖으로 내보내마
But retreating thirty li
30리 후퇴쯤이야
We can just come back
다시 돌아오면 그만입니다
Retreat thirty li then return
30리 후퇴했다가 돌아오면
Back and forth
가고 오는 데만 이틀은 허비합니다
In that case
그러는 사이에 경주군이 따라잡습니다
Brother-in-law
매형
As long as we act fast enough
신속하게 움직이기만 하면
There's still a chance
기회가 없는 것도 아닙니다
At that time
그때는
I'll lead the vanguard
제가 선봉에 서겠습니다